As 10 minutes is a short period of time to
get quite a bit done. I am… looks like
this mic is live since I'm going to leave
this here. I'll make this quick here. So,
I've been in working for companies like
Google, Microsoft, Amazon, and others for
the last 30 something years focusing on
technologies like authentication. And so,
today what I'm going to talk to you about
is what is digital identity. And this was
a little bit of bias in this, But I'm
going to try to get through about 30 years
of lessons in what I have left here. So
identity is not new. This is a picture of
a clay tablet from 1900 BCE. Merchants
used to put their thumbprint into these
clay tablets so that you could
authenticate that this is legitimate. This
is a point
that authentication is of transaction
actions is something that we've been
worried with since the dawn of time and
this is the earliest example I could find.
But we've been trying over and over to
solve this problem and each generation of
has to approach this problem slightly
differently for the environment that they
exist in. I've got a few examples that
exist in this timeline below here. We
won't go through them today, but at the
end of this presentation, I have a QR code
that talks a little bit about successes
that you can follow for a paper on
successes and failures in this space as
I'm going to go fairly fast here. So what
identity is not is as important as what
identity is. It is not a better document.
Digital identity is materially different
than the one-time issuance of a document
that we would use to authenticate at a
government office or when traveling. It is
more of a living type of credential that
lives for a long period of time. And that
living nature means that this is a
governance problem. This is not a
technology problem. So why is this
important? Because seven out of ten of the
projects that I've looked at over the last
several decades and then you'll see those
in that white paper have failed and they
failed because they looked at this as a
government not as a governance problem but
as a technology problem as IT or
procurement. And so that's why it's
important that we're all here today and
I'm really excited to be involved in this
conversation. So this is a model shift.
State issues document you carry it it,
verifier inspects it. That's what we're
all used to. But as we look at what does
it mean to have civic digital identity,
it's much larger than just my name is Ryan
Hurst. There's many endorsements about
Ryan Hurst that might be material to the
verification. I'm a motorcycle driver.
That is certainly a driver's license
thing, but I also am a parent. I also have
other attributes about me that are
important and the state is involved in
many elements of those and being able to
prove that to third parties is becoming
increasingly important and I'll talk a
little bit about some of those cases. This
expanded role of identity in the online
world is something that means that we have
to change the way we look at this problem
and we have to start with a set of guiding
principles which is why again I think SEDI
is an important project. So one of the
biggest differences that we'll see as we
look at digital identity versus our paper
history historical analog is that they
actually codify the policy that you all
come up with. And this is important
because now when you make a change, that
digital document and the systems that
verify it may also need to be changing. So
we have to think a little bit more
holistically than that issuance moment. We
have to think about how are we going to
manage this over its entire life cycle. If
we think of this as we bought a solution
to print these digital identities and
declare victory, we will fail. That's the
number one pattern we see when we look
back at the failed systems.
So what is maintained over time? Well,
there's a lot of status changes. Licenses
get suspended, whether it be medical or
driver's license or credentials may get
compromised and may need to be replaced.
Algorithms may need to be changed over
time. These are probabilistically secure
methods to prove these things and so we
may have to change them. For example, post
-quantum cryptography is coming in the
future. And policies change continuously
faster than ever before. And this all
means that how we govern these systems is
going to become increasingly important. So
if we look at these failure patterns,
there's many that we can point at. One of
the ones that I like to point at is the
German solution. Germany came up with a
national ID card that was technically pure
and perfect. From their definition of
technically pure, and perfect and it was
an abysmal failure. Nobody adopted it
because the governance model was not
right. They put the burden on the
constituents. They made it very
complicated to adopt. They didn't have a
core utility. So it was massive amounts of
money spent with no return on investment.
So not something that we can afford. UK is
another great example. I can't go into the
details today, but they wasted $233
million in a decade of time roughly
because they didn't look at this problem
holistically and they didn't measure it in
the right way. Some of the successes we
can point at Estonia. They started with a
list of three or four utility scenarios
that they were going to enable and as a
result, their system continues to exist.
We can look at Sweden. They looked at what
was practical to deploy and achieve
results with and their existing exists and
is loved. Very rarely do you find a
government service that is loved, but I
think that it's fair to say that that
particular program is. U.S. government has
its own as well and there's others that
have elements of success but we'll go into
those later in that paper I mentioned. So
why is this important? I'm from the state
of Washington. We have the honor of I
believe being the largest COVID fraud for
distribution of COVID funds. I think
Africa got more than we did. So this is a
big problem and it's a problem because we
didn't invest ahead of time. We didn't
build the infrastructure to enable the
government to be able to identify its
citizens online and we can't let this
pattern repeat again. So why does this
matter now? I mentioned COVID, but it's
much larger than COVID. We can look at AI,
for example. Today, I can generate a fake
utility bill, birth certificate, and
whatever easily with just a few types of
on my keyboard that you're going to
believe is legitimate. I can do real-time
deepfakes that are nearly impossible to
distinguish. The voice will be the same.
You cannot rely on a video call to
authenticate who you're talking to
anymore. And so this means that we have to
invest in infrastructure to be able to
strongly authenticate who we're dealing
with so that we're able to prevent
mistakes like that one from happening
again. I also think it's important to note
that in the context of security breaches,
88% of security breaches tracked by two
companies, roughly that figure, I think
they have two slightly different numbers
but very similar, were just using stolen
credentials. They didn't hack anything.
They logged in. And so it's important that
we pick strong technologies that solve for
the problems and don't have externalities
that make things worse. This is you are
the foundation of how the federal
government interacts with Americans. You
are the foundation of how the rest of the
world interacts with Americans online. And
we have to solve this problem. This is not
something that we can ignore. So why does
this matter for you? you don't manage
digital identity in abstract. There's a
lot of different examples of this that
exist inside of your organizations. You
may not think of them as digital identity.
Different people have different
definitions of this term, but I view all
of these things as part of the life cycle
of identity. A birth certificate is my
child's ID until they're old enough to get
a driver's license. Many of these other
elements, my wife carries our marriage
license because she's from another
country. When we travel because it's part
of her digital identity. All of these
things are part of that package that we
have to use, that the state produces, that
the rest of the world relies on to verify
who we are. So before you commit to any
approach, I think it's important to
understand what digital identity tells you
or what questions to ask. I didn't word
that particularly well. So since this is a
codified thing, the question becomes when
policy changes, how does the digital
identity get affected? it. Because it's
policy-based, how are you actually going
to create demand for this thing? If you
have no utility function for your
deployment, some scenarios that are
enabled that are actually meaningful to
your constituents, they're not going to go
through the hassle of doing it no matter
how beautiful the solution you build is.
Because it's how are you going to maintain
the entire life cycle of this system? This
is like any IT investment in that respect.
And because it's civic identity, you have
to pay attention to who's excluded. My
parents are not particularly good at using
things online anymore. And so we don't
want to exclude an entire segment of our
society and there's of course other
examples as well. So what does success
look like? You've identified anchor
tenants, you've budgeted some amount for
continual governance, you've addressed how
are you going to deal with
interoperability with existing systems,
you understand how your platform is
related to the various dependencies that
you have, and you understand the equity
implications for this system and how are
you going to manage them? And you've
defined success metrics and how you're
going to continually revise those metrics
so that you can make sure that your system
is delivering on the promises that you
should have set out to do. So that is my
presentations. Ladies and gentlemen, I
appreciate your time today.!